Agung Prakasya

Contact Information

E: agung.prakasya@outlook.co.id

 $M: +62 \ 8.1975.1975.0$

Personal Info

Born: Ciamis, 20 May 1975; Live in East of Cibubur, West Java; Nationality: Indonesian;

Language: Bahasa Indonesia & English

EDUCATION

Degree in Math Math Dept. of Bandung Institute of Technology, Bandung Majoring in Math Modelling;

April 2000

QUALIFICATION

Technology trends anticipating; Managing team of large size and/or high-skilled peoples; Mixing & matching personnels to achieve effective team composition; Excellent polyglot coder; Long-time *command-liner*; Very good on problem analysis and systematic solving, very good on statistical data analysis and math modelling.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Managed large multi sites team of 150s persons, including developers, operators and managers for a 3 years managed service project; Managed a team of 3 exceptionally high skilled persons for a nationwide project; Architected various systems: SCADA-enterprise integration, Bigdata migration, nationwide distributed biometric matching system, datastreams, Core Banking-stream offloading. 19 Years of total experience; 5 years in Bigdata and Datastream; 11 years of experience in energy industries: Oil & Gas and Mining —mostly on project management & specialist position;

EXPERIENCE

SIBERNETIK INTEGRA DATA-Jakarta

Determines company's technology related strategies including roadmap, stacks, team skill sets and partnerships.

Dec 2017–present Head of Solution Dev.

Q4.2019. Information War Campaign-BSSN

Technology Advisor

To provide media monitoring tools to BSSN regarding issues in social and formal media. Functions: Sentiment analysis, but detection, social media monitoring, etc.

- Q4.2019. Sistem Koordinasi Terpadu CAKRA–KOSTRAD Technology Advisor To provide media monitoring tools to KOSTRAD regarding issues in social and formal media, personnel distribution, war and peace strategies etc. Functions: Sentiment analysis, social media monitoring, etc.
- 2019--2020. Bigdata & Datastreaming Integration

Technology Advisor

-Commonwealth Bank

To provide Confluent Kafka data streaming solution to Commonwealth Bank Digital Banking. Functions: Realtime notification, realtime data ingestion, etc.

- 2019–2022. Bigdata & Datastreaming Integration—BRI Senior Solution Architect To provide Confluent Kafka data streaming solution to BRI Digital Banking. Functions: Realtime notification, realtime data ingestion, fraud detection, cash management, etc.
- Q3.2019. AIS live data streaming to Bigdata integration
 —Bea Cukai

 Technology Advisor

To provide Confluent Kafka data streaming solution to Ditjen Beacukai. Functions: Realtime AIS data streaming from multiple sources, on the fly data query, on the fly data quality etc.

- Q1.2019. Operational Dashboard–BAKAMLA Technology Advisor
 To provide dashboard solution to BAKAMLA for their strategic and day-to-day operation. Functions: Realtime notification, organizer, maps etc.
- Q1.2019. Ceria Payment Gateway—BRI

 To implement in-merchant-app payment page and BRI side gateway for BRI ceria microloan.
- Q4.2018. Ceria Collection System-BRI

 Technology Advisor
 To design & implement collection system for BRI Ceria, a microloan for online merchant's customers.
- Q4.2018. Ceria Merchant Dashboard–BRI

 To design & implement dashboard for BRI merchant (at the time this was written Tokopedia & Panorama)
- 2017–2018. Distributed Biometric Matching System Solution Architect, PM, Dev –Ditjen Imigrasi

To design & implement distributed biometric matching service for other subsystems in SIMKIM v.2 of Ditjen Imigrasi such as Izin Tinggal, Visa, Layanan Paspor, Cekal etc.

DATTABOT-Jakarta

Aug 2017-Dec 2017

To determine bigdata architecture and data migration methodology

Consultant

Q3-Q4.2017. **Bigdata migration-Bank Danamon** Sr. Solution Architect This project was to perform data migration from various data sources and core banking

system to client's new data warehouse. This project employ various technologies such as Cloudera Hadoop, Talend, Sqoop etc.

DOWEDO-Jakarta

Sep 2016–Jan 2018

To design system architecture and implement Online Tourism eCommerce platform

Consultant

2016–2018. Building Tourism eCommerce Platform

Solution Architect

This project was to build tourism e-Commerce platform. However the life cycle was ended when it reached MVP.

TRIPATRA ENGINEERS & CONSTRUCTORS-Jakarta

Nov 2013-Apr 2015

To ensure that project support systems keep aligned with all project requirements despite characteristics difference between projects.

Sr. Engineer

Q3.2014. Electronic Document Management System (EDMS) Project Manager —Internal project

This internal project objective was to develop a new major release of the system. The new release was the result of knowledge absorption from on going projects to keep the system aligned with future projects requirements.

Q2.2014. Issue Management System-Internal project

Project Manager

This internal project objective was to develop a system to manage projects issues. The main purpose of the system is, to track issue statuses, expedite for issue solutions and manage issue solution as lesson learned.

Q1.2014. Project Control Portal-Internal project

Project Manager

This internal project objective was to develop a centralized information service for the corporate on all projects project control. With this system, corporate are able to track progress status of the on going projects.

SINTESA SOLUSI UTAMA—Java, Kalimantan, Sumatera Feb 2006—Jun 2013 It was a self-owned company which was founded as information technology service provider.

2007–2013. Fuel Distribution Management System

Project Manager

(Java, Sumatera)–Elnusa Petrofin

This project was a managed service which provide IT service for client's whole fuel distribution operation, including IT systems, infrastructures and human resources.

Q3.2007. Interactive 3D simulation of Sidoarjo Mud Burst

Project Manager

-Lapindo Brantas

The project was to build interactive 3D simulation of the Sidoarjo mud on Banjar Panji site. This project used data provided by Lapindo Brantas to simulate the chronology of Sidoarjo mud burst and was to be presented by client to government and parliament.

Professional Service: Multi-remote Siemens WinCC integration

Aug 2011

Client: Perusahaan Gas Negara

OPC Specialist

The project was to integrate multi-stations Siemens Simatic WinCC which were distributed in different remote locations, South Sumatera and West Java using OPC communication standard.

Professional Service: WinCC-TOPServer Integration

Feb 2007

Client: Yamatake Berca

OPC Specialist

The project was to integrate Siemens Simatic WinCC and Yamatake TOPServer, using OPC communication standard for a Building Automation project.

Professional Service: SCADA-Enterprise Integration Client: Kaltim Prima Coal

Feb-Sep 2006 OPC Specialist

The project was to integrate the existing Siemens Simatic WinCC and corporate information system (Mincom Minetrak –a mining management solution), which was currently in implementation phase. The project was using OPC communication standard to stream data from the SCADA system. The project was implemented in a live production system which did not tolerate shutdown.

SIEMENS INDONESIA-Jakarta, Balikpapan, Handil May 2004–Feb 2006 MRS-H251 Obsolete ESD and F&G System Revamping Control System Engineer

The project was Obsolete ESD and F&G System Revamping in a plant operated by Total E&P Indonesie - East Kalimantan. The objective is to revamp shutdown system which was handled by ALSPHA and implement Siemens technology for the function. The project was also to integrate the system being implement to the existing system which was Honeywell DCS.

It was a project with a distinctive level of difficulties and risks, because it involved a live production system and diverse technologies, such as OPC (*OLE for Process Control*), redundancy support, failsafe and others. End result of the individual work here was an OPC sub-system which bridging communication between Siemens Simatic WinCC and Honeywell APPNode which conform to both communication and safety standard.

SELF EMPLOYED-Jakarta

2000-Dec 2004

Running self-owned internet cafe & gaming center along with

Business Owner

various sideline: such as printing services, photo-editing, banner & commercial design, billing system development, computer repair etc.

INTERESTS

Coding, guitar & basses, woodworking, gardening